

Phone: +92 320 4419651

Park View Villas, Lahore, Pakistan.

E-mail: zat98@gmail.com

Website: zaint10.github.io/portfolio/#/

Full Stack Software Developer

ME

Full Stack Software Engineer, possess versatile skillset & done variety of projects". Willingness to work with unfamiliar technologies and solid coding skills in JS, and Python.

I'm Adept in Front-End using React NodeJS. Fluent in Mobile/Hybrid development using Android/ ReactNative. Experienced in building CRUD applications, Web games and Desktop Applications (Python, Java C#, WPF). Know - how of ML, Data - science, Neural Networks & data wrangling. Well versed with algorithms, OOP, DSA, Design Patterns, Programming practices & SDLC.

PROJECTS

REACT PORTFOLIO Personal Portfolio built with React, React Router v4

Tools: create-react-app cli, react-router-dom, React MDL

Github Link

ANDROID APP/ FYP in Android-Java built using Material UI design concept

BLOODBUD Finding Potential Blood Donors now easier and hassle free. Orchestrated team

and assessed the SDLC together

Tools: Android, Firebase, Event Bus, Phone Authentication, Real-time Database

Github Link

REACT NATIVE/ (UNDER DEVELOPMENT) React native, Redux, Turbo360 as a RESTful API.

INSTAGRAM CLONE Core Features fetching Feed, like/Upload Post, access/update profile, Sign In/

SignUp.

Tools: React-Native, React-Navigation, Turbo360, Redux, Context API

Github Link

Rock-Paper-Scissor/ Front-End Web Application built using HTML/CSS and Javascript (E6)

WEB GAME Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript.

Github Link

TEXT Data Analysis, Visualization and Built Training Model

NORMALIZATION/ ML Initial Dataset provided by Kaggle, a Team project. Established Knowledge in

ML, Neural Networks, NLP and Supervised Algorithms

Tools: Python, Jupyter Notebook, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Scikit-Learn.

Github Link

FREELANCE/ StockVu – Stock Operations polished UI Built with Python PyQt

DESKTOP APPLICATION Tools: Python, PyQt Framework, Multithreading, File Handling, Import/Export Files.

Github Link

EXPERIENCE

FREELANCER

Freelance Projects (JAN 2019 – MAR 2019)

- Developed and Maintained StockVu Desktop App.
- Converted and Visualize Audio files.
- Design Mockups using Adobe Suite.
- Tutored various other projects and Software.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Intern / Exponento (Pvt) / (AUG 2017 – SEP 2017)

- Focused on user experience, and design responsive web based friendly user-
- Worked in accordance with agile, attending daily Scrums and working in a team.

SKILLS .

- HTML / CSS
- Javascript (ES6)
- Python / Java / C++ / C# / SQL
- React Js
- React Native
- JSX, Ajax, JSON, Firebase
- PyQt/ JavaFX/ WPF(C#) Android
 Git / GitHub Framework UI
- Picasso / Numpy / Pandas / Scikitlearn
- Matplotlib, Seaborn
- Google Maps / Phone Authentication Realtime Database.
- Heroku
- - **Adobe Suite/CoralDraw**

AWARDS -

&CERTIFICATES

Data Structures

Bootcamp: Algorithms + Data Structure | Udemy

Certification of Completion

C++ Tutorial Course | SoloLearn

Certification of Completion

Javascript

C++ Tutorial Course | SoloLearn

Certification of Completion

Java

C++ Tutorial Course | SoloLearn

Certification of Completion

Coding Knight

Stood 20th out of 32 teams in Coding Knights event.

Laptop & Scholarship

- Recipient of PEEF Scholarship for scoring merit marks in College.
- Awarded Dell Laptop for scoring position in High School.

EDUCATION -

PUCIT, University

Punjab University College of Information Technology

Completed 4 years Bachelors in Software Engineering.

Oct 2015 - Jul 2019

CGPA: 3.0